コードギアス反逆のルルーシュR2 TURN 10　神虎　輝く　刻
TURN 10　神虎　輝く　刻
The three great powers which control the world.
世界を支配する三大勢力 その中のふたつ
Two of them, the Holy Britannian
Empire and the Chinese Federation...
神聖ブリタニア帝国と中華連邦が
政略結婚によってひとつになろうとしている
are trying to become one by
means of a political marriage.
As this would be the greatest threat to the
United States of Japan, Zero has acted,
合衆国日本 最大の危機に ゼロは行動をおこし
by kidnapping the Chinese Federation's
empress, the symbol of the nation.
中華連邦の象徴 天子を奪うのだが
Can dreams cut a path through destiny?
夢は 運命を切り開くのか
Can your passion overcome everything?
思いはすべてを越えられるのか
Even though those things are ephemeral,
like flower petals fluttering in the breeze.
儚き花は　風に舞うのが常だというのに
Asa mo yoru mo koikogarete
Morning and night, I long for you
hoshi ni naru yo kimi mamoru
I'll become a star and protect you
tatakai wa yukue shirazu
No matter where the battle may take me
ashita to kinou no kousaten de
At the intersection of tomorrow and yesterday
majiwaranai kimi to boku
You and I can't be together
ima iku yo boku wa nagareboshi
I'm a shooting star, on my way right now
sekai ga kuchihatetemo
Even if the world crumbles apart
kawaru koto no nai mono ga aru
There are things which will never change
namida wo koraete demo
Even as we bear tears in our eyes
mamorubeki mono ga bokura ni wa aru
There are things we must protect
nanman'nen nan'okunen mae kara no
A message that's been in my body
message ga tainai de
For thousands and millions of years,
uzukidasu... mayoi wa nai
Springs out... I have no reservations
narihibiku... kantan da
Roars out... It's easy
shagareta koe de... asu wo yobu
In a hoarse voice... Calling tomorrow
kizudarake no te de... kimi mamoru
With my wounded hands... I protect you
I continue to fight...
I continue to fight!
asa mo yoru mo koikogarete
Morning and night, I long for you
hoshi ni naru yo kimi mamoru
I'll become a star and protect you
tatakai wa yukue shirazu
No matter where the battle may take me
ashita to kinou no kousaten de
At the intersection of tomorrow and yesterday
majiwaranai kimi to boku
You and I can't be together
sadame wo kirisaku nagareboshi
I'm a shooting star, tearing fate apart
afureru kimi no namida boku ga ima ubaisaru
I'll take away your overflowing tears right now
WHEN SHEN HU WINS GLORY
チャンリン様 想定通りで列席者が会場の外にでてきましたが
Lady Xiang-lin, while the attendees are
leaving the reception hall, as we predicted,
there are reports that Zero has shown up as well.
ゼロがあらわれたとの報告も
ゼロ？第３班 突入状況を報告せよ！
Zero? Section 3!
Report on your assault status!
第３班！シンクー様の援護はできているのか？
Section 3!
Are you providing backup for Xing-ke?!
まさか 我らの策がゼロによってつかわれている？
Could it be? Is Zero using our
plan for his own purposes?!
シンクー！
Xing-ke!
くっゼロ 天子様をかえす気はないのか？
Zero! Will you release Her Majesty or not?!
Xing-ke, you think you can free the empress?
You're mistaken!
シンクー 君なら天子を自由の身にできるとでも？
違うな
ナイトメアまで用意していたか
You even had a Knightmare prepared for this?
ふ まさか斬月の初仕事が花嫁強奪の手伝いとはな
I never thought the Zangetsu's first job
would be to help steal a bride away.
Tohdoh! Take care of Schneizel!
藤堂 シュナイゼルを
わかった
Understood.
もうきたのか
He's already here.
殿下はわたさない！
You won't get the prince!
Suzaku.
スザクくん
It can't be... Tohdoh?!
まさか 藤堂さんですか？
殿下 今のうちに
Your Highness, while we have this chance!
I suppose it can't be helped. Brother?
しかたないね兄上
う うん
シュナイゼル！
Schneizel!
あとは軍にまかせて我らも
We should leave this to the soldiers and go, too.
ゼロ こちらは予定通りです
Zero! We're on schedule on this end.
Right! Enter phase three!
よし サードフェイズに入る
わかりました
Understood.
シンクー！
Xing-ke!
よし　ここで
Right! Gotcha!
紅蓮と同じシステム？
The same system as the Guren?
So, it does work.
やはり いけるな
Then this Zangetsu will even let me
take on an opponent like Suzaku.
この斬月なら 相手がスザクくんであろうとも
しかし これなら！
Even so... With this, I'll...
Fool!
甘い！
撃てるかな この位置取りで
Can you shoot me in this position?
朱禁城を
The Vermilion Forbidden City...
まさか
Are they?
枢木スザク ここで！
Suzaku Kururugi, now taste defeat!
Kyoshiro Tohdoh! Still?!
藤堂鏡志朗　また
陰の 太刀
Shadow Longsword!
フロートぐらいで！
He got my float unit!
まだこんな武装が
You can still attack in that condition?
藤堂 そこはひとまずひけ
Tohdoh! Withdraw for now!
Just destroying the Lancelot's
float unit is good enough.
ランスロットのフロートを破壊しただけで十分だ
私たちをおうことはできなくなったからな
He won't be able to pursue us now.
Understood.
わかった
天子様 まもなく朱禁城の外に
Your Majesty, you'll soon be
outside the Forbidden City.
竜騎兵隊をまわせ天子様を
Surround them with the Dragon Cavalry!
Take back the empress...
And from this moment on,
that task will be ours to perform!
そこから先は 我らのお役目よ
Do they intend to escape using a gap
in our radar surveillance network?
当方のレーダー監視網その間隙をついて逃げるつもりか
Impossible!
They can't know of one!
ありえんしりうるはずがない
It's barely been 10 days
since the Japanese arrived here!
日本人どもがこちらに流れ着いてから10日もたっていないというのに
藤堂将軍 千葉の暁から補給をはじめますが
Gen. Tohdoh, we've begun
resupplying Chiba's Akatsuki.
わかった斬月と紅蓮はイカルガに戻ってからでいい
Understood. The Zangetsu and the
Guren can resupply aboard the Ikaruga.
All right, I'll arrange for that.
ではそれで手配を
よし 次は左だ
Okay, next left.
そうだったか？
You're sure?
Whoops! Wrong way.
あ違った！
Oh, you!
この！
大丈夫ですか？天子様
Are you all right, Your Majesty?
Is this... Are we outside?
ここが 外なのですか？
はいこのような乱暴な遣り方で
Yes. I'm sorry we had to make your
dream come true by such violent means.
天子様の夢をかなえることになろうとは
あ！おぼえていてくれたのですねあなたも
You mean you
remembered my dream, too?
もう！しつこすぎるよ！
Dammit, these guys
don't know when to quit!
ちょっとあっちいってな！
Just get lost, already!
Okay, next right.
よし！次を右
No, we head straight.
ちがう まっすぐだ
おまえ 道知ってんのかよ？
Do you know the way?
昔 ちょっとな
I was here once. A long time ago.
私達の国合衆国日本は
Our nation,
the United States of Japan,
should be thought of as just a part
of a giant union of united states.
もっと巨大な合衆国連合の一部であると考えている
あ はあ
合衆国中華 そのためにあなたが必要なのだ
Including a United States of China.
And for that, we need you.
すでに南部省インド軍区と話がついています
We've already received word from the Indian
military district in the southern province.
モンゴルやビルマも動くでしょう
Mongolia and Burma
will also likely make their move.
合衆国連合はブリタニアに対抗するための枢軸となる
The United States Union will
form an axis to oppose Britannia.
でも たしか我が国は連邦制で
But... Our nation is already
arranged as a federation...
システムにも寿命がある！
Even systems have limited life spans.
大宦官はおのが保身のためにあなたを売ろうとしたのです
That's why, for their own self-interests,
the High Eunuchs tried to sell you to Britannia.
許せることではない
And that is unforgivable!
あの 難しい話はその
Um... I'm not sure I understand all this...
天子様
Your Majesty...
リー シンクー将来をいいかわしたお方ですか？
Is Li Xing-ke the one
you discussed the future with?
えっ？そんな ただ 約束を
No, he...
He just made a promise to me.
いいなづけとして？
As your fiancé.
あ  その外に出たいと
Well, I... I told him I wanted
to go outside. Six years ago.
6年前に
そんなに昔のことを？
That long ago?
He must be destined for you!
運命の人ですね！
そ そうかしら
You... You think so?
How wonderful!
素敵です！
いいのか？神楽耶まかせで
Are you sure you want
to leave her to Kaguya?
どうも理屈で話すタイプではなさそうだからな
She doesn't seem like the type a
theoretical argument would work on.
苦手か
You don't like dealing with that?
It's hard to analyze
people like that.
分析しづらいだけだ
Say, Zero, have you come up
with a position for me, yet?
なあ ゼロ俺の役職ってまだきまらないのかよ？
I can't just stay a grunt like this.
いまさら ヒラでもねえし
財務大臣か　金融大臣のポストを
Maybe you can post me as
finance minister or head of banking.
You're the Grand High
Minister of Partying.
玉城は宴会太政大臣
そういう冗談はやめろって言ってるだろ！
I told you to quit
making fun of me like that!
なあ 俺たち親友じゃないかよ
C'mon, we're buddies, right?
Can we discuss that
once this crisis has passed?
その話は ここをくぐりぬけてからだ
えっ
なんだ？橋がなくなってるぞ！
What?! The bridge is gone!
こちら禁軍第４守備隊
This is Forbidden City forces, unit four.
対象は現在 竿中にて停止しています
Target is currently
stopped at Shen Chun.
おろかものが
Fools.
ふふふ予測どおりにはまってくれたな
They fell for it, just as I thought
they would. Asahina!
朝比奈！
Right, right.
はいはい
全軍 攻撃準備
All forces, prep for attack.
ふ 伏兵？！
An... An ambush?!
左右にも敵が！囲まれました
Enemy forces on the left and right!
We're surrounded!
What? Shoot them! Hurry!
ええい！撃て　撃てよ
No, wait! The empress!
待て天子様が
それじゃあ 新型の試し撃ちを
Okay, let's test out these new units.
追撃部隊がやぶれたのだろう？
They've taken out our
pursuit forces, haven't they?
なぜわかる？
How do you know that?
場所は竿中渓谷
They did it at the Shen Chun ravine.
私ならそこで兵をふせ陸軍を足止めする
That's where I'd stage an ambush
and stop the land forces.
それから？
And then?
小沛で本隊と合流するだろう
Then I'd join up with
my main force in Shao Pei.
ふうむ
シンクー 罪を許してもよい
Xing-ke, we're willing
to overlook your crimes.
天子様を取り戻せるのならな
Assuming you retrieve Her Majesty.
あれを貸し与えよう
We'll even lend you
the new weapon to do it.
How's Prince Odysseus?
オデュッセウス殿下は？
おちつかたようだね休んでおられる
He seems to have calmed
down at last. He's resting now.
では ランスロットのユニット交換が済み次第天子様を
Then once we've finished swapping out the float
unit on the Lancelot, I can go after the empress.
We can't pursue an further military action
unless the Chinese Federation requests it.
これ以上の軍事行動は 中華連邦からの要請が必要よ
それは 理解できますが
I understand, but still...
予想以上にスムーズだったな
That went even more smoothly than I imagined.
Perhaps that was all thanks to the
scheme Xing-ke and the others launched.
これもすべてシンクーたちが仕掛けてくれたおかげか
優秀だよ あの男は
He's a talented man.
どうして彼らがクーデターを画策しているとわかった？
How did you find out
they were plotting a coup?
私も同じ事をやろうとしていた
I was planning to do
the same thing.
ＥＣＭや伏兵もか？
Including the E.C.M. and the ambush?
ああ しかし想定ルートのひとつに誰かが先回りして仕掛けを施そうとしていた
Yes, but I found out some people were setting them
up ahead of us on one of the proposed routes.
I see... You got this plan
from one of the rebel soldiers.
なるほどその場にいた反乱兵から自白剤でも使ったか
Did you use a
truth serum on them?
ギアスという名のな
The one called Geass.
蓬莱島の状況は？
What's the situation
on Horai Island?
Reinforcements from
India have already arrived.
インドからの援軍はすでに到着しております
We just have to return and rendezvous with them.
How are things with the empress?
あとは帰って合流するだけだが
天子様の方は？
敵襲？先行のナイトメア部隊が破壊されていきます
Enemy attack?! Our forward
Knightmare unit is being wiped out!
とまれ！全軍停止だ！
All stop! All forces, stand-by!
Strange... I thought we'd have an hour
before we encountered enemy forces.
おかしい　敵軍と遭遇するにしてもあと1時間は必要だったはず
よんだやつがいるのか？こちらの動きを
Is there someone who's
guessed our movements?
A... A Knightmare?
ナ ナイトメア？
Zoom in! Hurry!
ズームだ！早く！
What's that?
あれは？なぜこちらと同じ飛翔滑走翼を装備している？
Why is it equipped with
the same flight wings that we use?
はぁ　なんだこれは
ナイトメアフレーム神虎
Knightmare Frame Shen Hu.
これでまだ出力40％
And it's only running
at 40% full output.
大宦官めなんてものを
How could the High Eunuchs
have made this?!
可翔型とはいえ 敵は一機
It may be flight-enabled, but there's
only one unit! Let's surround it!
囲んで叩きます！
ま まて
W-Wait!
You underestimate the
Shen Hu at your own peril!
この神虎を甘くみたな
Huh?!
Why, you!
よくも！
道理なきものがほざくな
You have no just cause to do this,
so be quiet!
きこえているか？ゼロ
Can you hear me, Zero?
まさか シンクーか？
It can't be! Xing-ke?!
ゼロ ここは通さん
Zero! I won't let you pass!
ですから どうしてこんなところでとまっているのかを
That's why I'm asking
why we've stopped here...
あ ああ そうですか
Oh, I see.
ええ ここは完全防音ですけど でも
Yes, it's completely
soundproof in here. But...
さあ 天子様を返してもらおう
Now then, return the empress!
今ならば命までは
Do it now, and I'll spare your lives.
シンクー！
XING-KE!
紅蓮可翔式！
The Guren flight-enabled version!
紅月カレンか？しかしこの神虎ならば！
Kallen Kouzuki, eh?
Even so,
the Shen Hu will defeat you!
斬月を出せるか？
Can we send out the Zangetsu?
それが ユニットをはずしたばかりでして
Well, we just detached
the float unit, so...
うあ～やっちまえ！カレン
All right! Let him have it, Kallen!
むちゃです補給前だったのに
It's impossible.
We haven't resupplied her, yet.
心配すんなあの紅蓮はナイトオブラウンズとも互角に戦ったんだぞ
Relax! That Guren was able to fight
off the Knights of the Round before!
飛び散れ！
Scatter!
やるね でも 私は黒の騎士団のエース！
Not bad. But I'm the ace
of the Black Knights!
みせてみろ 神虎 おまえの力を
Show me, Shen Hu!
Show me your power!
いけないあれは
Oh, no! That's!
しっているのか？
You know what it is?
あ その
Well... You see...
作ったのはうちのチームだからね
He knows because our team built it.
ラクシャータの？
Your team, Rakshata?
紅蓮と同時期に開発したんだけど
We developed it at
the same time as the Guren,
but it was so high-spec
that we abandoned work on it.
ハイスペックを追及しすぎてね
あつかえるパイロットがいなかった孤高のナイトメア
A one-off Knightmare
that no pilot could handle.
それが　神虎よ
That's the Shen Hu.
くらいな！
Eat this!
Try this!
受けてみよ！
大丈夫大丈夫ですから
It's all right!
We'll be all right!
天愕覇王荷電粒子重砲 これほどまでとは
The Ten-Gaku Ha-Ou charged
particle cannon. Just as powerful...
輻射波動砲弾と同じ破壊力！？
It's just as destructive
as the radiant wave surger!
それがなぜ敵の手に渡っている！
And why did you
give it to our enemies?!
インドも一枚岩ではないということでしょう
This means India isn't
completely behind us, doesn't it?
マハラジャのじじい
Damn that old man, Maharaja!
弱点はないのか？
Doesn't it have a weakness?
ほかのシリーズとは別の概念だからね
It's different concept from the other series.
輻射機構はないんだけど
It lacks a radiant wave system.
We just never found a good enough pilot...
あとはパイロットがいなかったってことくらい
そんな
Great. But there's someone
piloting it right now!
でも 今乗りこなしているやつがいるじゃないか
ねえ
True.
捕えたぞ勝敗は決した！
I have you!
Your defeat is decided!
そうね あなたの負け
True, as is yours.
なに
What?!
これであなたは逃げられなくなった
You can't run away now.
さあ じかにたたきこむよ！
Now I'll hit you directly!
そうか ならばしかたない
Really? Then I have no choice.
殺すのもやむなしだな
I'll have to kill you if you won't stop.
やれるものならね！
Try and do it!
エナジーが！
My energy!
カレン！
Kallen!
だから補給しろっていったのに！
I said she shoulda
resupplied first!
コックピットブロックが巻かれている
The cockpit block's wrapped up!
She can't eject!
あれじゃ脱出できない
挟撃で神虎のワイヤーを
Let's try a pincer move
and cut the Shen Hu's wires!
承知
Wilco!
このようなまねしたくはないが
I don't want to do this,
but I have an objective.
私には目的がある
天子様だ天子様を
The empress!
Hand her over to me!
At a time like this?!
こんなときに 反応しきれるか？今
Can I react properly now?
何？！
What?!
後方より 中華連邦軍大部隊です
Chinese Federation forces to our rear!
A huge force!
対空射撃も続けよシンクー様を援護
Continue antiaircraft fire!
Give cover fire for Master Xing-ke!
チャンリンか 助かる！
Xiang-lin! You're a lifesaver!
う やだちょっとまって
Oh, no... Wait, please!
カ カレンが
K- Kallen!
つかまった
She's been captured!
中華連邦軍にか
By the Chinese Federation forces?!
捕虜になる ？そん　そんな
She's their prisoner?! Impossible!
カレン！無線はまだ生きているか？
Kallen! Does your radio still work?!
す すみません失態を
S- Sorry, sir. I failed.
そんなことはいい！
Forget that!
あきらめるな必ず助けてやる！
Don't give up! I promise, I'll save you!
いいなへたに動くな！
Am I clear?! No false moves!
は はいわかっていますあきらめません　これ
R- Right!
Understood! I won't give up! I'll...
イカルガを回頭させるんだ今すぐ！
Bring the Ikaruga around! At once!
私は撤退を進言します
I suggest we withdraw.
なぜです？！カレンをとりもどさないと
Why?! We have to get Kallen back!
紅月カレンは一兵卒にすぎません
Kallen Kouzuki is just
one more combat loss.
見捨てろというのか？
We can't just abandon her!
南さん これは選択です
Mr. Minami, we have no choice.
中華連邦という国とひとりの命
A single life isn't worth the nation
known as the Chinese Federation.
くらべるまでもない
ここは兵力を温存し
We must preserve our military strength and hold
out till we rendezvous with the Indian forces.
インド軍との合流にそなえるべきです
ゼロ ご決断を
Zero, make the decision!
紅月隊長にはさきほどおかけになった言葉で十分です
It was enough for you
to comfort Capt. Kouzuki before.
これ以上は偏愛 ひいきととられ 組織がくずれます
If you show her any more favoritism,
our entire organization may fall apart!
ああ しかし
But!
情けと判断はわけるべきでは
You wouldn't let sympathy
influence your decision, would you?
大望を成すためには時に犠牲も必要です
Great ambitions sometimes
require sacrifices.
ルルーシュのヤツ
Oh, Lelouch...
あ ラウンズの
Oh. You're one of the Rounds.
決着をつける！全軍反転せよ！
I've made my decision!
All forces, turn about!
なぜです？！組織のためにも
Why?! The organization
is more important!
インド軍が裏切っている可能性もある
There's the possibility the Indian
forces have betrayed us, as well!
それは
Well...
千葉と朝比奈に鶴翼の陣を敷かせろ
Have Chiba and Asahina assume
a Crane's Wing formation!
シンクーにおしえてやる
Now we'll teach Xing-ke the difference
between strategy and tactics!
戦略と戦術の違いを！
あ ああ
R- Right!
ありがとう ゼロ
Thank you, Zero!
こちらは待機命令のままですよ
We've been ordered to stand by here.
そうねえ スザクくんは知ってた？
Oh. Say, did you know, Suzaku?
アールストレイム卿の携帯画像
About the picture Sir Alstreim
has on her cell phone?
あっいいの？
Oh. May I?
うん
Sure.
ああ そうか歓迎会きてたっけ
Oh, I see. You came to that
welcome party they threw for me.
ああ まずいよプライバシーが
Um, this isn't right.
It's an invasion of privacy...
あ ルルーシュ
Oh. Lelouch.
ルルーシュ？
Lelouch?
何やってるんだシャーリーがいるのに
What's he doing?
With Shirley right there with him!
ねえ
Right.
あ そうだ
Oh, that's right.
アッシュフォードへの連絡ですが今確認中でして
We need to contact Ashford,
but I'm still confirming it.
そうしかたないか
Really.
Well, it can't be helped.
心配してるだろうな～ルルーシュたち
Lelouch and the others
must be so worried about us.
これも ルルーシュ？
Is this also Lelouch?
黒の騎士団！全軍戦闘準備！
Black Knights!
All forces, prepare for battle!
地形は高低差が少ない
The terrain offers little cover, and the
geographic advantage isn't what we'd hope for.
地理的優位は望めない
In addition, the enemy forces
are improvised.
加えて敵の軍は急ごしらえ
指揮系統はゼロに集中するしかない
Their command network is
concentrated exclusively on Zero.
しかしナイトメアフレームの性能は敵がまさる
However, the enemy has the advantage
in their Knightmare Frames' capabilities.
となれば 中華連邦軍の選択肢は
Which means that the Chinese
Federation forces' choice will be...
神虎を前面におしたてての 中央
to put the Shen Hu on the front
line and then break through...
突破！
our center!
I'll stop the Shen Hu
with my Zangetsu!
神虎は　この斬月が！
第３竜騎兵隊射程ではこちらが勝る
Dragon Cavalry unit 3!
Our firing range is greater.
砲撃しつつ突進せよ！
Advance while firing!
敵の指揮官は抑えた暁隊 撃て！
The enemy commander's been blocked!
Akatsuki team, fire!
シンクーが動けずとも こちらは藤堂をおさえている
While Xing-ke can't move,
we've got Tohdoh pinned down as well!
ならば あとは兵士の熟練度が物を言う
In that case, this will be up to
the skill of each side's soldiers!
敵艦正面　天任区画を抑えろ
Hit the enemy ship head on
and secure their Ten-Nin section!
敵軍左右両翼は無視していい
Ignore the left and right
flanks of the enemy forces!
やはり紅月がいないと一手おくれるか
Without Kouzuki, we're one move
behind in this game!
中央が突破されました
They've broken through our center!
敵の本陣は？
Where's their main force?
かわらず正面です
Still on our forward line!
よし　条件はクリア
All right!
The conditions have been cleared!
反撃開始　右翼　千葉軍左翼　朝比奈軍
Begin counterattack!
Right flank, Chiba forces!
Left flank, Asahina forces!
パターンシグマを適用
Use attack pattern sigma!
後方射撃に備え 敵本陣に弾幕をはりつつ
Prepare for rearward fire!
Concentrate barrage on main enemy force!
先行部隊をたたけ
Strike the forward forces!
神虎をエナジー切れに誘い
Once we exhaust Shen Hu's energy
and neutralize Xing-ke, we can win.
シンクーをおさえればこちらの勝ちだ
すすめ！ここでとまれば我らは全滅するぞ
Advance!
If we stop here, we'll be wiped out!
カレンをかえしてもらう！
We're taking Kallen back!
つっこめーー！
Charge!
白兵戦にもちこむんだ！
We'll hold out with
hand-to-hand combat!
抜刀！
Draw swords!
援軍？！
Reinforcements?!
You've deployed all your forces
to try and finish us, Zero?
総力をあげてつぶしにきたか　ゼロ
なんとおろかな
How foolish!
神虎の力に頼りすぎではないか
Isn't he depending too much
on the Shen Hu's power?
In the end,
he's just a foolhardy warrior!
これではただの猪武者
いいえ これはゼロの出方をみるための策
No. This is just a way
to see how Zero will move.
この配置 その真の意味は
We'll soon see the real reason
for this arrangement of forces...
ふはははははシンクー運河の決壊がおまえの策か
Xing-ke, your plan was to rip
down the bank of the waterway.
しかし 水量は減らしておいたんだよ
But there wasn't as much
water as you thought!
とるにたらぬと考えたな
You think there isn't
enough to trap you?
ゆえにゼロ 君の負けだ
That, Zero, is why you've lost.
な なんだ？
Wh-What the?!
じ 地面が
The ground!
ここまさか
Wait, isn't this?
そう例の灌漑干拓地ですよ
Correct.
Reclaimed irrigation land.
癒着による手抜き工事とその結果はゼロも知らない
Even Zero couldn't know how political
corruption made the construction so shoddy.
先ほどの突撃は敵の主力を移動させるため
The charge before was to get the
enemy to move their main force.
シンクー様が単騎で先行したのは
Xing-ke went out as a lone rider in order to trap Zero.
この地にゼロを足止めするため
まさか読んでいたのか？
Impossible! He predicted it?
私が決戦を挑むとこの布陣をとると！
That I'd challenge him to a showdown
and deploy my forces like this?!
我らに勝利をもたらすは我が国の大地そのもの
What gives us victory is the
very land of our nation! Zero...
ゼロ　おまえの負けだ！
You've lost!
シンクーーーーー！
XING-KE!
まだ決着はついていない！
This battle is far from over!
さすがは奇跡の藤堂
Well done, Tohdoh the Miracle Maker!
しかし　敵の主力はここでとまった！
However, the enemy's main force
has been stopped right here!
全部隊 進軍開始！
All forces, advance!
臣遵旨
Chen Tsun Tsui!
敵ナイトメア部隊はあとまわしだ
Leave the enemy
Knightmares for later.
敵艦動力部に砲撃を集中！
Concentrate your fire on
the enemy ship's engine room!
対物理障壁も無尽蔵ではない
Their anti-physical barrier won't
hold out forever! Victory is ours!
勝利は我にあり！
この私が各個撃破にもちこまれた
Have they cornered me?
くっ醜態だ
What a disgrace!
ゼロ！私は進言しました撤退だと
Zero! I gave you my opinion!
I told you to withdraw!
いいだろう動力部を守りつつ　後退する
Fine! Protect the
engine room and withdraw!
ん？蓬莱島に戻っても
Even if we return to Horai Island...
I know! Ohgi,
what about the other place?
わかっている扇 例の場所は？
あ ああ
R- Right. We've finished a
preliminary recon and survey, but...
一応 偵察と測量はすんでいるから
認めよう シンクー
My hat's off to you, Xing-ke.
先におまえをおとすべきだった
I should have killed you first.
私と伍する知略とスザククラスの武勇
You're as clever as I am
and as good in battle as Suzaku.
天は二物を与えたというのか？
One could say heaven
blessed him twice.
でも 時間だけは与えてくださらなかった
But it didn't give him
enough time to live...
持ってくれ  もう少しだけ！
I have to hold on!
Just a little longer!
艦首 拡散ハドロン砲セット
Bow-mounted hadron
scatter cannon, set!
Gefjun control synch, good!
ゲフィオンコントロール　同調よし
Targeter aligned.
Ready to fire!
照準あわせ いけます
よし敵軍両翼にむけ 発射！
Right! Target both of
the enemy's flanks! FIRE!
さすがだな ゼロ
Impressive, Zero.
You still had a hand to play.
まだ手を残していたとは
各竜騎兵隊は散開　固まると狙われる
Dragon Cavalry, spread out!
They're aiming at groups!
藤堂は部隊の救出と再編成の指揮をとれ
Tohdoh, you rescue our troops
and take command to reorganize them!
イカルガは迂回しつつ　敵をひきつける
The Ikaruga will take an alternate
route to lead the enemy away!
第４予定地点に先行せよ！
Proceed to
rendezvous point 4!
めえ
中華連邦のニュース どこもながしてないみたい
It doesn't look like there's any news
about the Chinese Federation.
残存　全ナイトメア 回収完了しました
Recovery of all remaining Knightmares,
now confirmed.
MAUSOLEUM OF THE 88 EMPERORS
なるほどね
天帝八十八陵に たてこもろうってわけ
歴代の天子をまつるところ
I see. We're going to be holing up in the Mausoleum of the 88 Emperors?
Since past emperors are buried here,
たしかにここなら敵も攻撃しづらい
the enemy will think twice about attacking us.
敵は正面からくるしかないが
They can only approach us
from straight on.
その場合は艦首ハドロン重砲を撃てばいい
Then we can fire the
bow-mounted hadron cannon.
連射はできませんがね
We can't fire it continuously, though.
あとはインド軍を待つだけか
All we have to do now
is wait for the Indian forces.
くるはずないでしょ
I doubt they're coming.
援軍なき籠城戦ってこと
Besieged, with no reinforcements.
それだけならまだ交渉の余地はあったのに
In that case, there could have
still been room for negotiations.
大宦官がまさかあんな手を
I doubt the High Eunuchs
would have taken that option.
動くなと伝えたはず
I thought we told you
not to move.
我らに反旗を翻したものどもは許してなどおけぬ
We can't forgive anyone
who has plotted against us!
今はそんなときでは
Is this really the time
to bring that up?
それに 天子様を取り戻すのではないのか？
Or maybe you have no intention
of retrieving the empress!
ここまでで充分
This has been enough.
私たちには強大な援軍もいるしね
We also have powerful
reinforcements of our own.
どうする？
Now what? We never counted on the
Knights of the Round getting in on this.
ナイトオブラウンズまでは計算していなかった
愚かな
You fools!
この中華連邦で 他国の
Having foreigners intervene
within the Chinese Federation?
ブリタニア軍に援軍を頼むとは
Asking Britannia for aid?
And from the Avalon, no less!
しかもあの艦はアヴァロン
わかっているのか 大宦官どもは
Don't the High Eunuchs understand?!
相手はEUの半分を奪いとった男
That's the man who
stole half of the E.U.!
第二皇子シュナイゼルだぞ！
Schneizel, the second imperial prince!
大宦官は私たちだけではなく
The High Eunuchs seem intent on
wiping out Xing-ke along with us.
シンクーまでここで抹殺するつもりだな
ディートハルト 仕掛けの準備を
Diethard, get our little trick ready to go.
Wha?! Here?
ここでですか？
すべてそろった最高のステージじゃないか
Everything is in place.
It will make a most excellent stage.
勝ってみせるこの絶望的な状況からでも
I have to try and win!
Even in this hopeless situation!
続報が入りました中華連邦の情勢です
We now have an update on the
situation in the Chinese Federation.
クーデターの流れに乗じ ゼロがあらわれ天子を略奪したようです
Taking advantage of an attempted coup,
Zero appeared and kidnapped the empress.
天子の安否は
そうですか！無事なんですね 会長
Really?! You're okay then, Prez?!
うんスザクくんたちといっしょなんだけど
I'm with Suzaku and the others.
What's the news say on your end?
そっちのニュースは？
今 テレビやラジオはゼロ一色ですよ
The TV and radio's
just talking about Zero now.
よかった！会長生きてたよ
Thank God! The Prez is all right!
いずれにせよ 帝国臣民の敵 ゼロは
In any case, it seems that
Zero, the enemy of the empire,
海のむこうの中華連邦で最期をむかえることになりそうです
is about to meet his end across
the sea in the Chinese Federation.
Mune no naka itsuka hirotta
Someday let's try to pick up and rebuild
Shiawase no kakera atsumete miyou
The fragments of happiness in our hearts
Wasurekaketeita melody
That nearly forgotten melody
Iroasezu boku no man'naka ni
Stay vivid, deep inside of me
Arigatou kokoro kara
I thank you from the bottom of my heart
Boku ni ima ga aru no wa minna no okagesa
Everything I have now, I owe to everyone
Arigatou kokoro kara
I thank you from the bottom of my heart
Tsugi wa boku ga minna ni happy okuru yo
Next I'll send happiness to everyone
Nanimokamo wasurenai yo
I won't forget anything
Ano hi no boku mo boku dakara
Because I'm still the same as I was that day
Daisuki da yo'tte itsumo
You need me to keep on saying
Itte agenakya dame da ne
How much I love you
Namida ga kobore sou na nagai yoru wa
On those long nights, your tears about to overflow
Futto furikaette
Just turn around
Ashiato wo tadorun'da
Follow those footprints
Ano hi wo wasurenai you ni
So that you'll never forget that day
やってくれたなあ　この状況を
They've done it.
Now they've really gone and done it!
俺たちはただ追いつめられただけだ
Now even if I use my Geass on the empress
and make her my servant, it'll be meaningless!
勝利の確率は限りなく
いや　まだだ
Even Xing-ke is doomed to be
eliminated by the High Eunuchs.
この戦い　根底から覆してやる
In the end, we've just
ended up being cornered.
俺はここでおわるわけには
Even with Tohdoh and the others here,
Suzaku is bound to join the battle eventually.
今週ものプレゼントのお知らせです
好評発売中のNECのパソコン
There's almost no chance for victory...
コードギアスカスタムバージョンを一名様に
No, we're not finished yet!
これはギアスマークなどの紋章とキャラクターを自由に組み合わせるオリジナルのパソコンで
I'll turn this tactical battle upside-down!
I will not let this all end here!
今回はその中から　人気の組み合わせを刻印したモノをプレゼントします
POWER OF PASSION
詳しくは公式サイトをチェックパスワードを入力して
ご覧のケータイサイトから応募してください
今から一時間限定の受付です　特製待ち受けもゲット
ところで　ルルーシュ　君はずっと学園にいたのかい
当たり前だろ俺は学生だからなあ
ではあのゼロは
また来週！